BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

CLOUD PLATFORM ENGINEER – DELIVION MÜLHEIM AN DER RUHR

ONLINE

http://bharathkumaraju.com in in.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

github.com/bharathkumarraju

CONTACT Mülheim, NRW t: +49 15143155538

e: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com

BIO DETAILS

DOB: 12-June-1987 Passport: J7879295

Solutions Architect - Associate

Certified

amazon



SUMMARY:

Over 7 years IT experience in DevOps and CLOUD in mission critical environments across the Financial and GPS industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, automation, continuous deployment(CICD) pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

Able to communicate effectively at all levels and able to work on own initiative or within a larger group including during crisis situations.

TECHNICAL PROFILE:

DevOps AWS Cloud, Ansible, Puppet, Git, Bamboo, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx, Liquibase.

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeat, metricbeat, packetbeat.

Monitoring/Log Sysdig, Newrelic, Datadog, App Dynamics, Sumologic, sensu, flapjack, Grafana, graphite.

Programming Python, Shell Scripts, Java.

RDBMS Oracle, MS SQL, Sybase, PostgreSQL, MySQL. Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu. OS

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform.

Certifications AWS Solution Architect and VMware Cloud Professional

EXPERIENCE:

Delivion GmBH. Automated Bamboo deployments and builds using the Bamboo specs.

Implemented automated backup solution for complex applications. Germany

Worked in k8s setup and federated Prometheus monitoring for the k8s cluster and apps. (Mar 2018-Present)

Worked on SonarQube automation and upgrade using ansible.

Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD pipeline. StandardChartered,

Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic Stack. Chennai Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution. (Oct 2016-Mar 2018) Introduced Nginx as Gateway & Dockerized it with F5 as load Balancer.

Worked on Micro-service Architecture with spring config server for dynamic variable substitution in ansible.

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr/Terraform. Trimble Navigation,

Created Development, QA, Stage, Production stacks & maintaining them securely using robust VPC design. Chennai

Worked on REST API Development using AWS Gateway and AWS Lambda (Python). (Jun2014-Sep2016)

Automated resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving effort.

Implemented application monitoring using DataDog & integrated with AWS environment.

Performing Software installation, upgrade/patches, troubleshooting & maintenance on UNIX Servers.

Hewlett-Packard,

Administrated DHCP, DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments. Chennai Automating the deployment of Middleware Applications to RHEL DEV/PROD servers on VMWare ESX. (Mar2011-May2014)

EDUCATION:

MCA-Post Graduation Information System and Computer Science

(Jun2007-Jun2010) UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry **BSC- Graduation**

Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics. (Jul2004-May2007)

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi, German.

INTERESTS:

Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.